# Muhammad Haseeb

Sunrise Apartment, Block 1 Clifton, Karachi 03328278614 | haseebtes@gmail.com | **Available to relocate** 

## **Summary**

Insightful and proactive Engineer known for my ability to quickly establish rapport with clients & evaluating new business products. With a professional experience of more than one year in project management and sales at a multinational company, I have grown to be ambitious about understanding and meeting the needs of my customers. I believe in delivering quality and driving innovation at every step. Currently I am looking for a permanent role in an organization where I can contribute and grow with the company.

# **Experience**

#### SALES ENGINEER | SIEMENS | SEPT 2017 - FEB 2018

Client facing technical sales role in the Power Generation Services department in Siemens Pakistan

- · Provided technical support to clients for Compressors, Steam & Gas Turbines
- · Our team achieved 65% sales target of \$25Million within first 5 months of the fiscal year
- · Executed Remote Diagnostic and High-Speed Balancing project on SGT100 Gas turbine
- · Actively involved in preparing quotations, tenders and procurement of associated parts
- · Mapped the entire country's DresserRand fleet (400 Machines) after Siemens acquired their energy business
- · Streamlined order tracking with Salesforce based on analysis of current & pipeline projects

## ASST. PROJECT MANAGER | ZAFFAR ENTERPRISE | FEB 2017 - SEPT 2017

Project Management in a Local EPC Company in Pakistan working with electric utilities

- · Assistant lead in two high value projects for installing Energy Meters and Arial Bundled Cables
- · On site supervision including data entry of Site personnel and reviewing orders and invoicing on regular basis
- · Gained OHS & Quality Assurance accolades due to the standard of work which also lead to my promotion
- · Prepared cost estimates for a \$5Million Renewable Energy government tender
- · Lead in diversifying business in to industrial automation sector (PLC & HMI)

#### INTERN ENGINEER | SIEMENS | JAN 2017 - FEB 2017

Intern in the Power Generation Services department

· Wrote narratives and secured a permanent role with the company after a vacancy was made available

## **Education**

#### **B.ENG HONS.** | AUG 2016 | UNIVERSITY OF LEICESTER UK

First Class Honors in Electrical & Electronics Engineering

Related coursework: • Power Generation, Distribution & Transmission • Control Systems Theory

• Electrical Machines & Circuits • Power Flow Analysis • Management & Business

#### ALEVELS | AUG 2013 | BAYVIEW COLLEGE KARACHI, PAKISTAN

· Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry & Urdu

#### Skills & Software

- · CAD Software SolidWorks, AutoCAD & OrCAD Pspice
- · Microsoft Excel, Project & Word
- · Sales & Project Management
- · Perceptive communicator and excellent written and verbal skills
- · PLC/HMI software Siemens simatic step 7 200

# **Volunteer Experience & Achievements**

- **Formula Student UK** Battery Design Engineer in the biggest student motorsport competition being the only team with a custom design battery system, finished 3<sup>rd</sup> position in UK EV category
- · OXFAM Australia Worked as a volunteer in Sydney for a month to learn about global issues closely
- · University of Leicester UK- South Asian Scholarship holder and part of best Design & Business team
- · Bayview College Member of the student council and head of science & oratory society
- · Public Speaking Active debater having won several competitions and participated in HarvardMUN
- Dr. Ruth Pfau Hospital, Karachi Worked as a voluntary receptionist and guide for the old patients
- · Certifications Solar Energy & Product Design from University of Delft Netherlands online program

## References

Available on Request